# MANIKANDDAN GEDDY CHANDRASEKARAN

manikanddan.gc@gmail.com

+4915258753828 | Skype Id: gcmanikanddan1

http://in.linkedin.com/in/manikanddangc https://manikanddan.github.io/mgc/(Work in-Progress) Eppertshausen, Germany

7.5 years of experience in Digital Transformation Solutions working across various roles as Presales & Solutions Consultant, Product Management and Front-end Development. Blend of Software Engineering and Creative Design to reduce human machine gap by

## **COMPETENCIES**

UX: IA, Journey Maps,
Wireframes, Prototypes,
Usability Testing, Competitor
Analysis, Personas, Experience
Strategy, Content Strategy,
Heuristics Evaluation, Analytics,
A/B Testing, Lean UX, Design
Sprints, Web / Mobile Design
guidelines, Optimum User
Research Techniques.

*Tools:* Adobe XD, Illustrator, Photoshop, Invision, Sketch, Principle, Framer, After Effects

Design & Lang.: Layout, Typography, Color Schema, UI Components, Animations, HTML, CSS, JS, JSON

## **HONORS & AWARDS**

Won TCS Gem Points; 'On the Spot' award Path Breaker of the Year & Best New Entrant award (CTS) Brandon Hall Excellence Award & Best Project of the Year-2012 (CTS)

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

https://www.tcs.com/assuringmobility-for-the-internet-ofeverything https://www.tcs.com/blogauthors/manikanddangc

#### **STARTUP**

https://www.f6s.com/turuturu Selected as top 10 Proposals by one of State Governments in India assisted by WRI

### **EDUCATION**

2018 -2020 - M.A. Leadership in the Creative Industries Program, Hochschule Darmstadt University of Applied Sciences, Darmstadt, Germany

2006-2011 - M.S Software Engineering, VIT University, Vellore, India, 8.01 CGPA

### **EXPERIENCE**

### 2014-2018 | Tata Consultancy Services (TCS), Chennai, India

### Role: Product Strategy and Management – Created / Managed / Owned / Discovered

- Product Owner DQX
- UX Wireframes & Prototypes (iOS, Android, RWD)

creating UX with optimum User Research techniques, Lean design principles and analytics driven UX improvements.

- Product Features and Product Innovations
- Market Analysis and UX trends
- Product Roadmaps

- Product UX and Solution Model
- Product IA and role specific User Journey Maps
- Created Layout, Color Schema, UI controls, Typography
- User Research and Analytics
- Agile + Lean Execution

### Role: Presales & Solutions Consultant - Presented / Owned / Managed / Published / Discovered

- Worked in esteemed TCS Customer Experience Center
- In-Person presentations to F500 Customers
- Usability Framework for Mobile Apps
- Architectural Consulting for Machine Learning driven TCS QET Products
- Context Mapping of QET Products in Customer Environment
- Innovated '5 Stars' User Reviews Mining Engine

# 2013-2014 | Photon Interactive, Chennai, India

#### Role: Presales and Solutions Consultant - Presented / Owned / Managed / Discovered

- Web and Mobile UX Consulting
- Architectural Consulting
- RWD, KIOSKs, Mobile, Wearables
- UX Models for Industry Segments
- CRM Activities

- RFP/I/Proactive Opportunities
- Wireframes and Mockups
- Click through Prototypes
- C-Level Stakeholders and Startup with Studio Environment
- Success Story and Case Study

# 2011-2013 | Cognizant Technology Solutions (CTS), Chennai, India

## Role: Mobile App Developer – Developed / Managed / Learnt / Won

- Developed Animated UIs for iPad, Android and RWD Apps
- Agile Delivery Model

- Lifesciences, Healthcare, Manufacturing and Media Projects
- HTML / CSS / JS